The Agecroft Collection
The Agecroft Collection
- Documents relating to Walton in le Dale and the Cooper Family, 1545-1769; 2 sub-series, 29 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/7
  - Deeds relating to Walton in the Dale, 1545-1769; Chetham's Library; GB/418/81-100; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1
    - Probate of the will of Matthew Aldcroft, 6 Feb 1760; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 98; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/18
      Will dated 31 Jul 1759
    - Will of James Jolly, 12 Nov 1762; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 99; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/19
    - Bond from Matthew Aldcroft to Elizabeth Gant, 14 Apr 1769; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 100; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/20
  - Deeds relating to the Cooper Family of Walton in le Dale, 1688-[?1832]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/7/2
    - Assignment of a lease, 5 May 1688; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 6 no 101; GB/418/Agecroft/7/2/1
      From Daniel Chaddocke to John Cowper
    - Assignment, 1 Dec 1722; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 6 no 102; GB/418/Agecroft/7/2/2
      From William Garrard to Anne Garrard and Thomas Cooper
    - Assignment, 4 Jul 1724; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 6 no 103; GB/418/Agecroft/7/2/3
      From Anne Gerrard, Robert Hankinson and others to Edmund Cooper
    - Assignment, 2 Dec 1743; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 6 no 104; GB/418/Agecroft/7/2/4
      From Thomas Simpson to John Cooper
    - Lease, 18 Feb 1758; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 6 no 105; GB/418/Agecroft/7/2/5
      From Sir Henry Hoghton to John Cooper
    - Agreement, 8 Nov 1791; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 6 no 106; GB/418/Agecroft/7/2/6
      Between Alice Cooper and Kitty Cooper to Richard Hull
    - Assignment, 2 Feb 1792; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 6 no 107; GB/418/Agecroft/7/2/7
      From Alice Cooper and Kitty Cooper to Richard Hull
    - Accounts - heirs of late John Cooper, 1779-1785; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 6 no 108; GB/418/Agecroft/7/2/8
    - Probate of will of Kitty Cooper, [?1832]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 6 no 109; GB/418/Agecroft/7/2/9
      Will dated 13 Apr 1832
- Documents relating to Much Hoole co Lancs, 1717-1796; 24 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/8
  - Lease, 23 Sep 1717; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 110; GB/418/Agecroft/8/1
    From Richard Crooke esq of Macclesfield, co Ches to Christopher Buck of Tarlton, co Lancs
  - Assignment, 20 Nov 1731; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 111; GB/418/Agecroft/8/2
    From Mr Robert Buck of Much Hoole, co Lancs to Richard Fazakerly of [?Sallom] co Lancs
  - Lease, 24 Nov 1731; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 112; GB/418/Agecroft/8/3
    From Thomas Yates of Whitchurch, co Salop and others to Robert Buck of Much Hoole
  - Lease, 25 Nov 1731; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 113; GB/418/Agecroft/8/4
    From Thomas Yates and others to Robert Buck
  - Probate of the will of Robert Buck of Much Hoole, co Lancs, 1 Mar 1735; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 114; GB/418/Agecroft/8/5
    Will dated 13 Feb 1735-[6]
  - Account, 19 May 1753; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 115; GB/418/Agecroft/8/6
    Between Christopher Buck son and heir of Robert Buck late of Much Hoole, co Lancs, husbandman, decd, and the executors of the last will of the said Robert, concerning the estate and effects of the said testator.
  - Lease, 22 May 1753; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 116; GB/418/Agecroft/8/7
    From Mr Buck to Miss Leadbetter
  - Mortgage, 23 May 1753; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 117; GB/418/Agecroft/8/8
    From Mr Christopher Buck to Miss Hannah Leadbetter
  - Bond to perform covenants, 23 May 1753; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 118; GB/418/Agecroft/8/9
    From Christopher Buck of Liverpool co Lancs, apothecary to Hannah Leadbetter of Tarleton co Lancs, spinster
  - Release of all actions etc concerning the estate and effects of the said Robert Buck late of Much Hoole, 23 May 1753; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 119; GB/418/Agecroft/8/10
    From Thomas Iddon of Sowerby co Lancs, yeo, and Alice, his wife, late widow of Robert Buck late of Much Hoole, husbandman, and James Ffazakerley, to Christopher Buck, son and heir of the said Robert
  - Chirograph of a fine levied of lands etc in Much Hoole and Ribchester, 7 Sep 1753; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 120; GB/418/Agecroft/8/11
    Between Hannah Leadbetter, spinster, and John Haydock, plaintiffs, and Christopher Buck and Alice his wife, and Tempest Dewhurst and Margaret his wife, deforceants.
  - Release for a legacy left for Richard Buck by the will of Robert Buck, his father, 9 Apr 1759; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 121; GB/418/Agecroft/8/12
    From Richard Buck of Much Hoole co Lancs, yeo, to Christopher Buck, surgeon, his brother.
  - Will of Christopher Buck of Upholland, co Lancs, apothecary and surgeon, 5 May 1763; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 122; GB/418/Agecroft/8/13
  - Lease, 26 Jun 1764; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 123; GB/418/Agecroft/8/14
    From Ann Whittle of Preston to Evan Caunce of Mawdesley
  - Abstract of title deeds to an estate late the inheritance of Mr Christopher Buck, decd, in Much Hoole, 27 Jun 1764; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 nos 124 & 125; GB/418/Agecroft/8/15
    The estate is now mortgaged to Mr Evan Caunce for securing £260 16s 0d and interest, 1717-1764.
  - Lease, 2 Apr 1771; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 126; GB/418/Agecroft/8/16
    From Richard Hull to Hugh Parker
  - Lease, 2 Apr 1771; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 127; GB/418/Agecroft/8/17
    From Richard Hull of Chorley to Richard Watkinson of Much Hoole
  - Lease, 6 Jan 1789; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 127*; GB/418/Agecroft/8/18
    From Mrs Alice Buck of Poulton to Edward Tassicar of Much Hoole
  - Lease, 2 Feb 1796; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 7 no 128; GB/418/Agecroft/8/19
    From Robert Buck of (?) and Richard Buck of St Mary Magdalen College, Cambridge to Hugh Norris of Much Hoole
  - Declaration of Trust, 18 Feb 1772; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 bdl C no 10/33; GB/418/Agecroft/8/20
    From John Cooper to Mr Richard Hull
  - Lease of a premises in Much Hoole, nd [?18th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 bdl C no 10/34; GB/418/Agecroft/8/21
    From Robert Richard Buck to Hugh Norris.
  - Lease for a year, 17 Feb 1772; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 bdl C no 10/35; GB/418/Agecroft/8/22
    From Evan Caunce to John Cooper
  - Assignment of a mortgage in fee of a messuage, tenement and lands in Much Hoole co Lancs, 18 Feb 1772; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 bdl C no 10/36; GB/418/Agecroft/8/23
    From Evan Caunce and others Mr John Cooper
  - Mortgage, 27 Jun 1764; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 bdl C no 10/37; GB/418/Agecroft/8/24
    From Richard Hull and others to Evan Caunce
- Documents relating to the Manor of Ambleside, 1747-1878; 32 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 nos 10/1-10/32; GB/418/Agecroft/9
  In 1878 Agecroft Hall passed to Lieutenant Robert Hull, eldest son of RP Hull Brown of Ambleside, and great nephew of the deceased Catherine Dauntesey Foxton. Hull took the name Dauntesey, in accordance with a clause in Catherine's will.
  - Manor of Ambleside: Admission of Thomas Partridge, 18 Jun 1747; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/1; GB/418/Agecroft/9/1
  - Manor of Ambleside: Admission of the Rev William Cookson, 27 Jan 1780; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/2; GB/418/Agecroft/9/2
  - Manor of Ambleside: Admission of Mackereth Bateman, 16 Oct 1804; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/3; GB/418/Agecroft/9/3
  - Memorandum of an agreement between Robert Partridge of Gail House in Ambleside in the parish of Windermere co Westm, gent, and Thomas Jackson of Waterhead in Ambleside, gent, 13 May 1805; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/4; GB/418/Agecroft/9/4
  - Fine of 4 shillings paid by Mr William Benson of Kirkby Lonsdale co Westm, tanner, for admission as tenant of closes of land at or near Low Fold in Ambleside, 28 Nov 1834; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/5; GB/418/Agecroft/9/5
  - Conveyance by way of exchange of a Dale in Birdhouse in Ambleside co Westm, 14 Feb 1838; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/6; GB/418/Agecroft/9/6
    From James Brancker, esq, and another to William Benson.
  - Fine of 10 pence paid by William Henry Partridge of Vauxhall co Surrey,esq, for admission to a close called Wanlass How in Ambleside co Westm, 8 Jun 1840; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/7; GB/418/Agecroft/9/7
  - Admission of John Buckley, 8 Jun 1840; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/8; GB/418/Agecroft/9/8
  - William Henry Partridge. Fine 2 shillings, 8 Jun 1840; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/9; GB/418/Agecroft/9/9
  - William Henry Partridge. Fine 1 shilling, 8 Jun 1840; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/10; GB/418/Agecroft/9/10
  - Conveyance [?of Newlands], 26 Apr 1841; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/11; GB/418/Agecroft/9/11
    From Mr William Benson to John Brenchley, esq
  - Map to show the lands conveyed by the indenture of 3 Feb 1842, Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/12; GB/418/Agecroft/9/12
  - John Brenchley esq. Fines 1s 7d, 21 Feb 1842; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/13; GB/418/Agecroft/9/13
  - Admission of John Buckley, 27 Aug 1844; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/14; GB/418/Agecroft/9/14
  - Inland Revenue. Succession Duty on real property of John Brenchley, 1855; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/15; GB/418/Agecroft/9/15
  - Admission of AC Brenchley. Fine 2s 6½d, 26 Dec 1859; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/16; GB/418/Agecroft/9/16
  - Admission of John Brenchley. Fine 2s 6½d, 26 Dec 1859; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/17; GB/418/Agecroft/9/17
  - Admission of Rev Julius Lucius Brenchley. Fine 2s 6½d, 26 Dec 1859; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/18; GB/418/Agecroft/9/18
  - Admission of John Brenchley. Fine 2s 6½d, 27 Dec 1859; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/19; GB/418/Agecroft/9/19
  - Admission of John Brenchley. Fine 2s 6½d, 28 Dec 1859; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/20; GB/418/Agecroft/9/20
  - Admission of John Brenchley. Fine 2s 4d, 20 Jan 1860; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/21; GB/418/Agecroft/9/21
  - Schedule of deeds and documents relating to a place called Newlands situated in Ambleside in the county of Westmoreland, 1875; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/22; GB/418/Agecroft/9/22
  - Admission of the Revd JL Brenchley. Fine 9¼d, 21 Jan 1860; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/23; GB/418/Agecroft/9/23
  - Admission of John Brenchley. Fine 9¼d, 21 Jan 1860; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/24; GB/418/Agecroft/9/24
  - Admission of John Brenchley. Fine 9¼d, 22 Jan 1860; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/25; GB/418/Agecroft/9/25
  - Admission of AC Brenchley. Fine 9¼d, 21 Jan 1860; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/26; GB/418/Agecroft/9/26
  - Admission of John Brenchley. Fine 9¼d, 23 Jan 1860; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/27; GB/418/Agecroft/9/27
  - Conveyance [of Wanlass How], Ambleside, 18 Feb 1860; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/28; GB/418/Agecroft/9/28
    From John Brenchley to John Brooks. Attested copy
  - Wanlass How. Admission. John Brooks. Attested copy, 12 Mar 1860; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/29; GB/418/Agecroft/9/29
  - Covenant for the production of deeds. Wanlass How. David MacIver with James Marshall Brooks, 1 Mar 1872; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/30; GB/418/Agecroft/9/30
  - Abstract of the title of James Marshall Brooks to a field called 'Newlands'… Received 14 Aug 1878, Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/31; GB/418/Agecroft/9/31
  - Account. Robert Dauntesey to WH Heelis, 1878; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 10/32; GB/418/Agecroft/9/32
- Miscellaneous deeds relating to Manchester, 1318-1760; 15 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 319-332*; GB/418/Agecroft/10
  Includes deeds between the Hulmes, the Marlers, the Sandeforths and the Burdmans relating to a messuage in Manchester situated at the east end of the church-yard of Manchester. In 1544 this land was sold to Robert Langley of Agecroft.
  - Grant of a burgage in Manchester co Lancs, (1318); Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 319; GB/418/Agecroft/10/1
    From Robert son of Hugh del Milnegate, to Richard his son. Henry Boteronde, provost of Manchester, is a witness.
    [?12] Edward 2
  - Lease of a burgage in Manchester co Lancs, 16 Jun 1469; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 320; GB/418/Agecroft/10/2
    From Alice Cale the wife of William Hulme, John Hulme her son and heir and Geoffrey Hulme son and heir apparent of the said John to Thomas Marler of Manchester for the term of five lives.
    3 seals.
    16 Jun 19 Edward 4
  - Lease of a burgage in Manchester co Lancs, 15 Mar 1515; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 321; GB/418/Agecroft/10/3
    From James Hulme, son and heir of James Hulme esq, late decd, and John Chetham and Clemens his wife, mother of the said James, to Hugh Marler son of Ralph Marler of Manchester, shireman.
    Term: 99 years
    15 Mar 6 Henry 8
    1 broken seal
  - Assignment of a lease of a burgage in Manchester co Lancs, 12 Jul 1520; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 322; GB/418/Agecroft/10/4
    From Hugh Marler of Manchester to Rauff Sandeforth.
    21 Jul 12 Henry 8
    1 seal
  - Deed poll of a burgage etc in Manchester co Lancs, 1 Apr 1524; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 323; GB/418/Agecroft/10/5
    From James Hulme esq and Clemence Chetham, his mother, to Ralph Sandeforth and his heirs for ever.
    1 Apr 15 Henry VIII
    2 seals
  - Release of a term, 26 May 1525; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 324; GB/418/Agecroft/10/6
    From Janet Marler, widow, late wife of Hugh Marler of Manchester decd, to Hugh Burdman her brother of all her term in a burgage in Manchester.
    26 May 17 Henry VIII
    1seal
  - Release of a burgage in Manchester co Lancs, 4 Jun 1525; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 325; GB/418/Agecroft/10/7
    From Ralph Sondeforth to James Hulme esq and Clemence Chetham widow, his mother.
    4 Jun 17 Henry VIII
  - Conveyance of a messuage in Manchester co Lancs, 22 Nov 1540; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 326; GB/418/Agecroft/10/8
    From William Crompton and Agnes his wife to Hugh Burdman, father of the said Agnes.
    22 Nov 32 Henry VIII
  - Grant of burgages eyc in Manchester co Lancs, 24 Nov 1540; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 327; GB/418/Agecroft/10/9
    From Hugh Burdman of Tetlawe, to William Crompton and Agnes his wife, on condition that the said William Crompton and Agnes keep and clothe Cicely Burdman daughter of the said Hugh, for her life.
    24 Nov 32 Henry VIII
  - Conveyance of a burgage in Manchester co Lancs, 20 Jun 1544; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 328; GB/418/Agecroft/10/10
    From Hugh Burdman to Robert Langley of Agecroft esq on condition that he clothe and feed John and Cicely, children of the said Hugh, during their lives.
    20 Jun 36 Henry VIII
  - Appointment of attorneys by Robert Langelyof Agecroft esq to receive possession of a burgage in Manchester, 20 Jun 1544; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 329; GB/418/Agecroft/10/11
  - Surrender of a messuage etc in Manchester co Lancs, 10 Jul 1703; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 330; GB/418/Agecroft/10/12
    From John Hinde of Manchester, clerk, to Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft co Lancs esq, to the intent that a common recovery may be suffered of the same.
  - Share certificate in the Mersey and Irwell Navigation Company allotted to Thomas Gartside of Manchester, 10 Jun 1724; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 331; GB/418/Agecroft/10/13
  - Copy of articles of agreement made previous to the marriage of Robert Billinge of Manchester, gent, with Elizabeth Holt of Manchester, merchant, 7 Feb 1760; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 332*; GB/418/Agecroft/10/14
  - Lease of a messuage in Manchester, from John Leigh of Warrington co Lancs to Elizabeth Dauntesey of Manchester, widow, gentlewoman, 29 Aug 1753; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 10 no 332; GB/418/Agecroft/10/15
    Term: 21 years, if she so long live
- Documents relating to members of the Buck Family, 1782-1895; 1 sub-series, 129 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/11
  When the direct line of descent was broken the estates became vested in John Hull. He died in 1813, and was succeeded by his brother-in-law Rev Richard Buck, son of Christopher Buck, a landed proprietor near Preston. He in turn was succeeded by his son John, who, in 1867, took the name of Dauntesey. When John died unmarried the estate passed to his sister Catherine Dauntesey Foxton. Catherine died in 1878 and was succeeded by her great nephew Lieutenant Robert Hull, eldest son of RP Hull Brown of Ambleside. Hull took the name Dauntesey, in accordance with a clause in Catherine's will.
  - Grant of a rent of nine shillings and four pence for lands at Edgecroft in the Wapentake of Salford, co Lancs, 15 Jun 1826; Chetham's Library; GB/418/no 278; GB/418/Agecroft/11/1
    From the King to the Rev Richard Buck of Edgcroft Hall, near Pendleton, co Lancs
  - Merger of tithes by Richard Ed Heathcote of Longton co Stafford, esq and Frederick Phillips of the city of Manchester, esq and others, 13 Jul 1848; Chetham's Library; GB/418/no 279; GB/418/Agecroft/11/2
    The lands…in the said township of Pendlebury…the messuage called Agecroft Hall.
    Merger of that charge by Robert Buck Esqr of Agecroft Hall co Lancs, 20 Aug 1852.
    Envelope including duplicate declaration of merger of tithes of Robert Buck esq of Agecroft Hall Estate in Eccles parish with a memorandum of confirmation by the commissioners.
  - Notice of intended application to Parliament by East Lancashire Railway, 2 Dec 1852; Chetham's Library; GB/418/4/1; GB/418/Agecroft/11/3
    Bill no 1. Robert Buck and Elizabeth Hall. No 1 Township of Pendlebury. Parish of Eccles.
  - Measurement and value of Rev Mr Dauntesey's land in Pendlebury and Pendleton, Agecroft, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/4/2; GB/418/Agecroft/11/4
  - Bill for making and maintaining a navigable canal from Manchester to or near Presto-lee Bridge in the Township of Little Lever and from thence by one branch to or near the Town of Bolton, and by another branch to or near the town of Bury, all in the county Palatine of Lancaster, 1791; Chetham's Library; GB/418/4/3; GB/418/Agecroft/11/5
    31 Geo III
  - Bundle labelled 'copies which RB considers of not much importance', nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/4/4; GB/418/Agecroft/11/6
  - Lease of Parkhouse Estate and other lands, 7 Jul 1813; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/5; GB/418/Agecroft/11/7
    From John Hull to William Thomason
  - Petition to Dr Buck from Claughton and Fitchett, 19 Apr 1817; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/6; GB/418/Agecroft/11/8
    Dated at Warrington
  - Letter to Dr Buck from Edward Forshaw, 15 Dec 1827; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/7; GB/418/Agecroft/11/9
  - [Document] between John Dauntesey of Agecroft and Michael Norton, 25 Dec 1800; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/8; GB/418/Agecroft/11/10
  - Deed of Covenants respecting a sum of £150 deposited with Mr Hull as a collateral security for performance of covenants in a lease, 1 Sep 1813; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/9; GB/418/Agecroft/11/11
  - Counterpart of lease Rigby Molyneux to Thomas Simpson, [24 Oct 1742]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/10; GB/418/Agecroft/11/12
  - Declaration in the Common Pleas at Lancaster in England, [10 Jul 1844]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/11; GB/418/Agecroft/11/13
  - Document re James Cookson and Amberside land, 17 Sep 1787; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/12; GB/418/Agecroft/11/14
  - Agreement between Mr Dauntesey and Mr Westbrooke, [1802]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/13; GB/418/Agecroft/11/15
  - Draft agreement for the sale of coals at Agecroft in the County of Lancaster, 1826; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/14; GB/418/Agecroft/11/16
    From Andrew Knowles esq with the consent of Rev John Buck and his wife to Charles Purcell esq
  - Office copy certificate of the payment of Dr Bucks purchase money into the bank, 7 Jan 1817; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/15; GB/418/Agecroft/11/17
    Crosse v Ormerod
  - [Document] concerning Mr John Dauntesey, Michael Morten, nd [19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/16; GB/418/Agecroft/11/18
  - Lease for a year, 1 Jul 1817; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/17; GB/418/Agecroft/11/19
    From Thomas Legh esq and others to Robert Buck
  - Bond for payment of rent and performance of covenants, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/18; GB/418/Agecroft/11/20
    From Mr Norton and others to Rev Mr Dauntesey
  - [Document] signed by Charles Wood re land at Chorley previously owned by Timothy Lightoller, decd, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/19; GB/418/Agecroft/11/21
  - Duplicate lease of the coal mines under the Agecroft Hall Estate in the County of Lancaster, 16 Aug 1823; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Bdl 11 Misc docs no 4/20; GB/418/Agecroft/11/22
    From Rev Richard Buck and Margaret his wife to Miss Elizabeth Hull
  - Counterpart lease, 28 Sep 1830; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 1; GB/418/Agecroft/11/23
    From Rev Richard Buck and Miss Hull to Thomas Taylor
  - Continuation Abstract of title of Thomas Legh Esq and his Trustees to Estates in Hoole, Brotherton, Eccleston and Ulness Watton in the co of Lancaster, mortgaged to Wm Fox esq, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 2; GB/418/Agecroft/11/24
  - Abstract of Mortgage of estates in Hoole and elsewhere in the county of Lancaster, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 3; GB/418/Agecroft/11/25
    From Thos Legh esq and his Trustees to William Jones and William Fox esqs. For Mr Forshaw
  - Statement of Personal Estate of Mrs Dauntesey Foxton, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 4; GB/418/Agecroft/11/26
  - Order confirming Dr Bucks purchase, 10 Dec 1816; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 5; GB/418/Agecroft/11/27
  - Letter to Edward Forshaw, 1 Aug 1818; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 6; GB/418/Agecroft/11/28
  - Declaration of Trusts: Mr Edward Heath as Trustee for Mrs Foxton, 8 Sep 1870; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 7; GB/418/Agecroft/11/29
  - Account from Robinson and son to the Executors of the late John Hull esq, 30 Mar 1895; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 8; GB/418/Agecroft/11/30
  - Debenture bonds for the Manchester, Sheffield and Lincolnshire Railway, 19 Apr 1855; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 9; GB/418/Agecroft/11/31
  - Rent statement for Agecroft Hall Estate, Pendlebury, 11 May 188[1?]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 10; GB/418/Agecroft/11/32
    Elias Dorning and son in account with Robert Dauntesey, esq. Dated from January to December 1880
  - Bond for securing the payment of the certain rent reserved by a lease of mines, 1843; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 11; GB/418/Agecroft/11/33
    From Mr Andrew Knowles to Miss Hull and Robert Buck
  - Account of the personal estate of John Dauntesey esq, decd, consisting of moneys and securities, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 12; GB/418/Agecroft/11/34
  - Assignment of certain interests in household furniture and effects at Agecroft Hall, 3 Aug 1855; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 5 no 13; GB/418/Agecroft/11/35
    From Messrs R and J Buck to Miss Hull